ARNOLD BRECHT PAPERS (GER024) 1865-1974
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- Correspondence, 1905-1976; 2; 319 file folders
  - OMGUS (Office of Military Government for Germany), including, 2.8
    - Wells, Roger H., 1947; 1952; 1962 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - HICOG (High Commissioner for Germany), including, 2.9
    - Conant, James B., 1940; 1952-1957 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Dillinger, L. E., 1950 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Hunter, David R., 1949 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Mason, John B., 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - HICOG (High Commissioner for Germany), including, 2.10
    - McCloy, John J., 1950-1952 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Stone, Shepard, 1945-1964 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Wolfsperger, Ellsworth, 1949-1951 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Zink, Harold, 1946-1950 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Embassies ( Canada, England, India), 1943-1961 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - German Bundestag members visit to U.S., 1950 May (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - German Consul General, New York, including, 2.13
    - Curtius, Klaus, 1964-1971 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Federer, Georg, 1959-1964 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Krauss, Georg, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - German Consul General, New York, including, 2.14
    - Posadowsky-Werner, Harald Graf von, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Rhamm, Ulrich von, 1962-1964 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Riesser, Hans E., 1932; 1951; 1966-1968 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Schmidt-Schlegel, Philipp, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - German Consul General, Washington, including, 2.15
    - Grewe, Wilhelm G., 1955-1961 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Knappstein, Heinrich, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Krekeler, Heinz L., 1951-1957 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Pauls, Rolf, 1970; 1972 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Correspondence with German public officials, 2.16
    - Correspondence with German public officials, 1935-1965 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Adenauer, Konrad, 1948-1964 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Anders, Georg, 1955-1972 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Boettcher, Erich (Bürgermeister von Lübeck), 1951-1968 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Brandt, Willy, 1957-1976 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Braun, Otto, 1932-1955 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Brüning, Heinrich, 1937-1966 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Ebert, Friedrich, 1921-1922 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Ebert, Karl, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Erhard, Ludwig, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Friedensburg, Ferdinand, 1935-1972 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Gerstenmaier, Eugen (Bundespräsident), 1959; 1961 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Heinemann, Gustav W., 1967-1970 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Heuss, Theodor, 1948-1966 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Kaiser, Jakob, 1950-1956 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Kohl, Helmut, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Kroeger, Hans, 1949-1954 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Lex, Ritter von, 1951-1957 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Löbe, Paul, 1934-1964 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Lübke, Heinrich, 1959; 1964 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Oppler, 1951-1952 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Pünder, Hermann, 1948-1956 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Scheel, Walter, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Schmid, Carlo, 1952; 1974 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Schmidt, Helmut, 1974; 1976 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Schmidt, Wolfgang, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Schumacher, Kurt, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Schröder, Gerhard, 1954-1972 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Suhr, Otto, 1952-1957 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Wehner, Herbert, 1963-1971 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Weichmann, Herbert, 1941; 1972-1976 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - New School for Social Research, correspondence on special programs and with other faculty members, 2.17
    - New School for Social Research. General correspondence, 1942-1973 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Peace Research Project, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Institute of World Affairs, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Bad Godesberg Peace Conference, 1974 June (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Ascoli, Max, 1940; 1944 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Colm, Gerhard & Hanna, 1939-1960 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - David, Henry, 1959-1963 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Deyrup, Felicia (Johnson), 1960-1971 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Everett, John R., 1966-1971 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Greenbaum, Joseph J., 1968-1976 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Greene, Murray, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Heilbroner, Robert L., 1968; 1970 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Heimann, Eduard, 1942-1967 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Hovde, Bryn J., 1945-1949 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Hula, Erich, 1943-1947 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Johnson, Alvin, 1933-1949 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Johnson, Alvin, 1950-1969 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Jonas, Hans, 1959-1967 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Kallen, Horace, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Landynski, Jacob, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Lowe, Adolph, 1944-1972 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - MacIver, Robert M., 1943-1964 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Mayer, Carl & Trude, 1942-1974 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Mayer, Clara, 1951-1965 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Neisser, Hans & Charlotte, 1949-1972 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Padover, Saul K., 1950-1971 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Pekelis, Alexander H., 1944 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Salomon, Albert, 1942-1966 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Schutz, Alfred, 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Simons, Hans, 1934-1955 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Simons, Hans, 1956-1963 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Simons, Hans & Eva, 1964-1969 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Simons, Hans & Eva, 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Speier, Hans, 1937-1972 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Staudinger, Hans & Else, 1935-1977 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Todd, Elizabeth, 1953-1961 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Vidich, Arthur, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - White, Howard B., 1955-1965 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Wunderlich, Frieda, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence with organizations, institutes, etc, 2.18
    - American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - American Civil Liberties Union (Roger Baldwin), 1946-1951 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - American Council for Emigrés in the Professions, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - American Friends Service Committee, 1944-1947 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - American Political Science Association. Annual meeting, Washington, D.C., 1939 December 28-1939 December 30 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - American Political Science Association. Annual meeting, Chicago, 1940 December 27-1940 December 30 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - American Political Science Association. Correspondence, 1941-1942 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - American Political Science Association. Round Table on Comparative War Administration, 1943 January 30 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - American Political Science Association. Round Table on A Federal Solution for Europe, 1944 January 20-1944 January 23 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - American Political Science Association. Research Committee: Beyond Relativism in Political Science, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - American Political Science Association. Annual meeting, 1953 September (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - American Society for Political and Legal Philosophy (John Ladd), 1959-1964 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - American Society for Public Administration (Don K. Price, Robert J. M. Matteson), 1942; 1959; 1965 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Army Specialized Training Program, 1943-1944 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Including correspondence with: Walter Knittle, Fritz Karsen, Warner F. Brook, Bernard Levy, Paul Tillich, William Sollmann.
    - Commission on the Organization of the Executive Branch of the Government ( Hoover Commission), 1948-1952 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Commission to Study the Organization of Peace, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Control Office for Germany and Austria ( London), 1946 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Council for Democracy (Harry B. Price), 1941 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Council of Jews from Germany, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Institut zur Förderung öffentlicher Angelegenheiten, 1950-1951 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Institute of Jewish Affairs (Beryl Harold Levy), 1941 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Institute on World Organization (Laura Puffer Morgan), 1942 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - The International League for the Rights of Man (Roger Baldwin), 1951 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - International Political Science Association, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Leo Baeck Institute, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Loyal Americans of German Descent, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - National Peace Conference, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Pan-European Conference (Richard Graf Coudenhove-Kalergi, Arnold Zurcher), 1943 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - The Rockefeller Foundation, 1948; 1955 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Social Science Research Council, Special Committee on Comparative Administration, 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Survey of Foreign Experts (U.S. Government), 1943-1944 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - United European Federalists, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Universities Committee on Post-War International Problems, Conference on Treatment of Germany, 1943 July 17 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Writings of Arnold Brecht, 1904-1976; 3; 198 file folders
  The writings of Brecht have been divided into two sub-series: 1) full-length book publications; and 2) essayistic and literary writings.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Subseries 1: Full-length (Book) Publications, 1906-1974; 3.1; 34 file folders
    This series contains early publications by Brecht during his years in the Reich Ministries and the Reich Chancellry, as well as manuscript material to his later publications. The bulk of this sub-series is comprised of materials dealing with his major publication, Political Theory: The Foundations of Twentieth Century Political Thought, first published in 1959 in English, reprinted editions, and the translation into German. This includes text materials, reviews and correspondence between Brecht and his publishers.
    - Vom Verkauf einer fremden Sache. Dissertation (1906). Original text & photocopy, Undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Geheim-Diplomatie. Von Dr. Arn. Br. HANSON (1918). Original text & photocopy, Undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Die Geschäftsordnung der Reichsministerium. Ihre staatsrechtliche und geschäftstechnische Bedeutung. Zugleich ein Lehrbuch der Büroreform, 1927 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Reichsreform. Warum und Wie?, 1931 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Die Sanierung des Reichshaushalts im Kabinet Brüning-Dietrich, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - "Relative and Absolute Justice. An Introduction to Modern Political and Legal Philosophy". Book proposal and outline, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Prelude to Silence. The End of the German Republic, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      Review.
    - Federalism and Regionalism in Germany (1945). Correspondence, notes, Undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Governing Postwar Germany, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      Reviews.
    - The Political Philosophy of Arnold Brecht, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      Reviews, correspondence.
    - "Unhysterische Historie". Outline of planned essay volume, 1955 April 15 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Gemeinsame Geschäftsordnung der Bundesrepublik, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Wiedervereinigung. Drei Vorlesungen, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Wiedervereinigung. Drei Vorlesungen. Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Political Theory. The Foundations of Twentieth Century Political Thought, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      Pages with corrections.
    - Political Theory, Undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Political Theory, Undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Political Theory, Undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
      Review, other languages.
    - Political Theory. Additions and corrections to the paperback (5th) edition, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Political Theory. General correspondence, Undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Political Theory. Readers' comments, Undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Political Theory. Correspondence with Princeton University Press, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Political Theory. Correspondence with Princeton University Press, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Political Theory. Correspondence with Princeton University Press, 1960-1967 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Political Theory. Correspondence with J. C. B. Mohr (Paul Siebeck) on German edition, 1959-1976 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Political Theory. Correspondence with Curtis Brown Ltd., 1959 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Political Theory. Correspondence with Irmgard Kutscher concerning German translation, 1959-1961 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - The Political Education of Arnold Brecht, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - The Political Education of Arnold Brecht. Correspondence with Princeton University Press, 1963-1970 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Aus nächster Nähe. Lebenserinnerungen 1884-1927, Undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
      Author's annotations and corrections.
    - Mit der Kraft des Geistes. Lebenserinnerungen 1927-1967. Author's annotations, Undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Aus nächster Nähe and Mit der Kraft des Geistes, Undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Kann die Demokratie überleben, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Lyrisches Vermächtnis, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      Editorial corrections.
  - Subseries 2: Essayistic and Literary Writings, 1904-1976; 3.2; 165 file folders
    This series contains Brecht's contributions to newspapers and periodicals, as well as individual chapters in books. Included in this series are early writings in German, including several literary pieces. Although many of the typescripts are present only in photocopies, original newspaper and magazine clippings or reprints of the majority of published pieces are present in this series.
    - "Entwürfe literarischer Art", 1904-1908; handwritten pages (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - "Der Traum der Treue. Eine Novelle", 1906; typescript (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - "System der Vertragshaftung (Unmöglichkeit der Leistung, positive Vertrags-verletzungen und Verzug", 1908 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - "Bedingung und Anwartschaft. (Das aufschiebend bedingte Eigentum, seine Bestellung, Weiterübertragung und Pfändung)", 1911?; printed text (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - "Erzberger, Oberste Heeresleitung und Waffenstillstand", 1921 September 13 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      Printed text, with related articles by other authors.
    - "Die Ausgaben der deutschen Reichsverwaltung. Versuch einer genauen Übersicht", ca. 1922-1923; reprint (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - "Die Hoheitszeichen des Reiches", after 1922; printed text (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - " Berlin als Reichshauptstadt", 1923 October (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - "Aufzüge", 1925 November 20 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      Periodical issue.
    - "Die Büroreform in der Verwaltung", 1926 May 1 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - "Die neue Behördenregistratur", 1926 October 20 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - "Polizei in Versammlungen?", ca. 1926; printed text (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - "Reformierter Bürokratismus", 1926 November 25 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - "Die Sammlung des Reichsrechts", 1926 December 15 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - "Das Reich-Länder-Problem". Stettiner Vortrag, 1927 October 12 (Box 9, Folder 19)
      Mimeographed text; printed version; reactions to lecture, clippings.
    - "Neujahr -- Wohljahr!", 1928 January 1 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - "Für ein Gesetz über Nachprüfung der Verfassungsmässigkeit von Reichsgesetzen", 1928; printed text (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - "Maßnahmen zur Vereinfachung der Staatsverwaltung", 1928; printed text (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - "Papier und Geschichte. Reichsverfassung 1919 und 1871, Wilsons Punkte", 1929; mimeographed text (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - "Suche nach der Zauberformel. Das Viererreferat zur Reichsreform", 1929 March 29 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - "Gemeinschaftsarbeit", 1929 June 21 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Review of Handbuch des deutschen Staatsrechts, 1929 September 21 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - "Der Vorrang der Seele. Zum heutigen Todestag Walther Rathenau", 1931 June 24 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - "Reichsreform und Notverordnung", 1931 August 28 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Speech by Brecht on "Unparteiische Amtsführung", 1932 December 15 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - "Realpolitik und Reichsreform", 1933 February (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - "Distribution of Governmental Powers Between Federal State and Local Government" (OMGUS), 1947 November (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - "Der unvollkommene Rechtsstaat. Die Tragödie der deutschen Demokratie vor 1933 als Beispiel", 1950 July 12 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - "Die Idee eines 'Sicherheitsgürtels'", 1955 June 4 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - "Gangbare und ungangbare Wege. Zur Frage der Wiedervereinigung", 1955 July 17 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - "Alternative der Wiedervereinigung. Gangbare und ungangbare Wege", 1955 August 27 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - "Wege zur Wiedervereinigung", 1956 January 3 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - "Geisel gegen Geisel" (Letter to the Editor, 1972 September 28 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Copies of essays and shorter pieces by Brecht, assembled by the author, with some notes and correspondence, Undated; 3.2.34 (Box 10, Folder 1-11)
      - "Collected Papers of A.B. (1906-1912)" (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - "Collected Papers of A.B. (1917-1919)" (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - "Collected Papers by A.B. 3. 1922 to 1929" (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - "Collected Papers by A.B. 4. 1930 and 1931" (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - "Collected Papers by A.B. 5. 1932 and 1933" (Box 10, Folder 5)
        Includes copy of Vereins- und Versammlungsrecht, Republikschutz und Ausnahmerecht, 1932.
      - "Collected Papers by A.B. 6. 1934 to 1938" (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - "Collected Papers by A.B. 7. 1939 to 1942" (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - "Collected Papers by A.B. 8. 1943 to 1949" (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - "Collected Papers by A.B. 9. 1950 and 1951" (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - "Collected Papers on Germany", 1927; 1944-1950 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - "Collected Papers on Politics", 1939-1952 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - "System der Vertragshaftung (Unmöglichkeit der Leistung, positive Vertragsverletzungen und Verzug)", 1908; reprint (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - "Die einfache und die wiederholte positive Vertragsverletzung", 1909; reprint (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - "Bedingung und Anwartschaft. (Das aufschiebend bedingte Eigentum, seine Bestellung, Weiterübertragung und Pfändung)", 1912?; reprint (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - "Realpolitik und Reichsreform". Draft, 1933 February (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - "Civil Service", 1936 May (Box 10, Folder 16)
      Reprint (copy), notes.
    - "Bureaucratic Sabotage", 1937 January (Box 10, Folder 17)
      Reprint, notes.
    - "The New Russian Constitution", 1937 May; reprint (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - "Democracy Today and Tomorrow. Lessons from Central Europe". Lecture notes, 1938 November 1 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - "Public Service in the U.S. and Abroad". Harvard lecture, 1938 December 9 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - "Sovereignty". Chapter from book, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - "Relative and Absolute Justice", 1939; reprint (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - "National Conference on the United Nations, State Dept. Building, Jan. 14, 1939". Text with corrections, Undated; photocopy (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - "The Relevance of Foreign Experience". Book chapter, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - "The Search for Absolutes in Political and Legal Philosophy", 1940 May; reprint (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - "Political Basis of a Durable Peace". Text of speech, 1940 May 10; mimeograph (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - "Durable Peace After France's Surrender?" Text of speech, 1940 July 2; mimeograph (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - "Efficient Administration -- A Nazi Miracle?", 1941 (Box 10, Folder 28)
      Text of speech, typewritten, photocopy.
    - "Three Topics in Comparative Administration -- Organization of Government Departments, Government Corporations, Expenditures in Relation to Population", 1941; reprint (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - "The Impossible in Political and Legal Philosophy", 1941 March; reprint (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - "The Myth of Is and Ought", 1941 March; reprint (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - "Smaller Departments", Summer 1941; reprint (photocopy) (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Appleby, Paul H. and Arnold Brecht. "Organization for Overhead Management", Winter 1942; reprint (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - "European Federation -- The Democratic Alternative", 1942 February; reprint (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Social Science Research Council. "Summary of Discussions on Overall Administration, Washington, D.C., May 1, 1942", Undated; photocopy (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - "Regional Organization Within World Organization, Extent and Reciprocal Relations". Institute on World Organization, 1942 September 12 (Box 10, Folder 36)
      Photocopy of speech text.
    - "Comparative War Administration". American Political Science Association, Round table discussion, 1943 January 30 (Box 10, Folder 37)
      Photocopy of round table notes.
    - Social Science Research Council, Committee on Public Administration, Special Committee on Comparative Administration. "Memorandum on Regional Coordination", 1943 March; mimeographed text (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - "Limited-Purpose Federations", 1943 May; reprint (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Memorandum Regarding Problem IV as Formulated by the University Committee on Post-War International Problems". Pan-European Conference, Summer 1943; photocopy of typescript (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - "Distribution of Powers Between an International Government and the Governments of National States", 1943 October; reprint (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - "Courses for Prisoners of War", 1943 November 10 (Box 10, Folder 42)
      Photocopy of proposal.
    - "On Germany's Postwar Structure", 1944 November; reprint (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Social Science Research Council, Special Committee on Comparative Administration. "Summary of Discussions on the Streamlining of Departmental Headquarters, Washington, D.C., May 29, 1945", Undated; mimeographed text (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - "Memorandum on Constitutional Problems in Germany", 1946 January 7 (Box 10, Folder 45)
      Mimeographed text of proposal.
    - "New Conceptions Affecting Research in Comparative Government", 1946 (Box 10, Folder 46)
      Photocopy of speech text, American Political Science Association.
    - "Democracy -- Challenge to Theory", 1946 June; reprint (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - "Government and Our National Economy", 1946 December 28 (Box 10, Folder 48)
      Photocopy of speech notes, American Political Science Association.
    - "Civil Service Abroad. I. Civil Service Reform in Germany. Problems and Suggestions", 1947 January; reprint (Box 10, Folder 49)
    - "Walther Rathenau and the German People", 1947 February; reprint (Box 10, Folder 50)
    - "Beyond Relativism in Political Theory", 1947 June; reprint (Box 10, Folder 51)
    - "Gutachten zur Neuordnung des Dienstes in der öffentlichen Verwaltung", 1947 June 28; photocopy of text (Box 10, Folder 52)
      Also related correspondence.
    - "The Idea of a Safety Belt", 1949 October; reprint (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - "The New German Constitution", 1949 December; reprint (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - "Struggling for Peace", 1949 December; reprint (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - "German Civil Service Today", 1950; mimeographed text (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Walther Rathenau und das Deutsche Volk. Pamphlet, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - "Re-establishing German Government", 1950 January; reprint (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - "The Concentration Camp", 1950 June; reprint (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - "Probleme des öffentlichen Dienstes in den Vereinigten Staaten von Amerika", 1950 December 1; reprint (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Einaudi, Mario, Jean-Marie Domenach and Aldo Garosci.Communism in Western Europe, 1951 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      Review by Brecht.
    - "What Is Becoming of the German Civil Service?", 1951 April; reprint (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - "Strategic Diplomacy. American Defense in Europe: Political Implications and Alternatives", 1951 October (Box 11, Folder 11)
      Mimeographed text of paper.
    - Voegelin, Eric.The New Science of Politics: An Introduction, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Essay on learning American English, ca. 1952; photocopy of handwritten text (Box 11, Folder 13)